Sophie Chen

UX Designer

706-201-6214 | sophie.chen13@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a highly empathetic designer fueled by my passion to create authentic, meaningful, and inclusive experiences for people. I am personable, communicative, adaptable, and strongly believe in the importance of being a team player.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Designer & Marketing Consultant - May 2020 to Present

- Work collaboratively with local entrepreneurs to create the logo and visual design for their company
- Discuss and implement marketing and communication strategy to help entrepreneurs grow their brand
- Build and maintain company websites for various local businesses

Strategy Research Consultant (Freelance) - SHM, London, UK - July 2020 to September 2020

- Provided insights from global market research to help Managing Director develop COVID-19 strategy
- Helped reimagine leadership development programming for clients' senior leadership

Marketing Coordinator - Liberty Exteriors LLC, Atlanta, GA - May 2017 to August 2019

- Conducted market and competitive analysis to inform the overall Go-to-Market Strategy
- Established brand style guide and designed all print and digital marketing materials to improve CRM
- Built the company's website and Facebook page and associated assets to keep followers and clients engaged with new and original content

Editorial and Marketing Intern - 1776 VC, Washington, D.C. - August 2016 to May 2017

- Developed industry reports for Managing Directors looking to grow presence in health, education, transportation, sustainability, and smart cities
- Wrote and managed content for 400+ start-ups in the 1776 network, showcasing them on the VC's website
- Assisted the Managing Director of Global Marketing to ensure all materials produced were consistent with the brand style guide
- Supported SEO optimization for corporate events, insights articles, and online content
- Worked with Business Development on the strategy and campaign to target key players at SXSW who would be interested in 1776

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry - Certificate in UX Design - 2020 to 2021

Specializations: UI and Frontend Development

American University, Kogod School of Business - BSc in Business Administration - 2013 to 2017

Specialization: Marketing

KEY SKILLS

Platforms and Software: Adobe XD, Balsamiq, Canva, Figma, InVision, Sketch, Squarespace, Wix, Wordpress

Digital Analytics: Google, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram